Sony sponsored this unboxing of the
WH100XM6 overear active noise cancelling
headphones with a claim that I got to
wonder, can they even legally say the
best noise cancellation? Yes.
Apparently, they went through a whole
bunch of certifications and tests so
that in their marketing they could say
it has the best active noise
cancellation. I hope I didn't break it.
We have a midnight blue model here. Oh.
Ah, yes. Made for iPhone. Hey Google.
Supports high-res Bluetooth audio.
That's cool. What does 30 hours of
battery life times 2 mean? Depends on
settings, environmental conditions, and
usage. Actually, that's a big deal
because not only does it have an array
of microphones to handle its active
noise cancellation, but it has advanced
processing on board that allows it to
adjust the active noise cancellation in
real time, contributing to an
improvement that we measured in our I
have to disclaim this draft version of
our audio testing suite from the lab
significantly improves over the XM5s.
Not as much in the bass range where
you're going to be cutting out the
rumble of an aircraft engine or the
sound of a train going over the tracks,
but especially up in the mid-range. It
is like seriously what 15 dB better or
something like that. That is a big
improvement. Sony sound connect. We're
going to need an app because everything
does a Yeah, buddy. You get a 3 and 12
mm cable because hey, Sony is one of the
few manufacturers that still puts a
headphone jack on their top-end models.
Shout out Sony's other division. On my
tiny hands, they look like quarterinch
jacks. As well
as a charging cable that doesn't shout,
I'm compensating for something. Made in
Vietnam. Hey, that's convenient in the
current climate. I like this little
pocket for them, but not as much as I
like that the XM6 mark a return to
folding for Sony's overthe-ear
noiseancelling headphones. It just feels
so thick. I do wonder if that
contributes to the great sound isolation
that we got out of those. To be clear,
sound isolation is its ability to block
outside noise before you have enabled
any active noise cancellation. Wow, they
really Dude, this is like I'm not
endorsing using them for this, but this
is like putting on freaking hearing
protection. Apparently, this is pretty
typical for headphones in this class.
So, maybe I'm just a little bit out of
the loop, but it feels really good to
me. About 30 dB at 1,000 hertz. So,
that's in like your typical speaking
frequency. and as low as 40 dB or even
more in the higher frequency range. But
it's the A&C that we're really
interested in for these. So, why don't
we fire them up? Actually, no. Why don't
we take a closer look at them first? We
have very, very light padding on the
headband. Though, to Sony's credit,
they've managed to deliver a contoured
shape that doesn't dig into my head at
the apex, which is something that I've
run into many times in the past. And
while they have what I would definitely
describe
as pretty solid clamping pressure, it
doesn't contribute to significant
discomfort for me. At least not
immediately. And that's due to a couple
of things. Number one is
the really really soft memory type foam
that's on the ear cups here. And another
thing is the adequate sizing of the ear
cups. You can actually see that my ear
comfortably fits inside. For me, any
pressure on the top or the bottom of the
lobe is an absolute dealbreaker, and
it's less obvious. But check this out.
If I poke at the cloth in here, okay,
you can see that in some spots it's
solid, and that's fine because that's
where my ear is deeper. But in some
spots there's actually gaps back there.
So that means that it doesn't put
pressure on here either, which is a
major source of discomfort for me. This
gives it an overall balanced head hug
feel, which probably contributes to the
excellent consistency that we found
between mounts when we were mounting it
to our uh hats or head and torso
simulator that doesn't have a torso.
Look, I don't name these things. All
right. One thing to note, by the way, is
that even if you do get a bad mount,
Sony has done an excellent job of using
the built-in microphones to compensate
for that, boosting the bass output of
the headphones in the event that there
is a little bit of leakage, which is
causing its impact to be reduced. That's
a big improvement over the last gen XM5.
All right, that's a microphone button.
That's a headphone jack button. What do
you mean headphone jack? I mean, it's a
headphone jack button. off. Okay.
USBC button. By the way, you can charge
and listen at the same time. That's
pretty handy. Charge indicator. uh got a
power button. Then we got this guy to
toggle between noise cancelling and
ambient mode. Though it is worth noting
that within the app, you can actually
turn on a hybrid mode that will
automatically try to adapt so that you
can hear important things but block out
stuff that you don't want to hear so
much. Like that baby that's crying on
the airplane. Me personally, I love
listening to babies crying on the
airplane. That's why I fly
coach. Man, this is like walking into
the sound chamber. Yo, it's a little bit
eerie. No way. Did Andrew say something
just now? Okay, I know this is sponsored
and all that, but holy
Oh man, I can hear it a little
bit, dude. I don't even have music
playing yet. Okay, how's the pass
through? Whoa, buddy. Especially coming
out of noise cancellation freaking
isolation land. It sounds like I'm I'm
talking into a PA system and it's like
being broadcast at me from the speakers
everywhere. That dude, that's that's
wild. Can it handle Belle's 90 Hz voice,
though? We actually found the bass
extension on these
was quite excellent. So, it should be
able to do it. Okay, Bell. Let's see how
natural your voice sounds. Hello, I am
speaking to you, Lionus, in my normal
speaking voice. I'm still talking. Do I
sound normal? Only you can tell. I can't
do it that quick cuz it takes a second
to dial in. So I hit Hit me again. Hit
me again. Uh Z YX W V U T S. Really
close. That's damn close. And then it
takes like 2 and 1/2 seconds to kind of
dial itself in. To be clear, I don't
think it's taking 2 and 1/2 seconds.
They're talking about they got what,
like 12 microphones, new processor,
seven times faster. But it's more of
like a hysteresus thing. They don't want
to just immediately have things kick on
and off because it can be quite jarring,
especially with active noise
cancellation. With that said, I find
this ANC not super jarring to kick on
for me because it has very little very
little kind of pressure effect. And I'd
say the more disconcerting thing about
it is just how silent everything feels.
It's like when you're watching like a
space movie, okay, and the background
music is going when they're inside the
station or whatever and then it it cuts
to them out on the spacewalk and they
have that intentional cut in the
background music and everything goes
quiet. That's what it's like when the
ANC kicks on for these. It's wild, dude.
Listening mode,
standard background music mode. The idea
being that background music mode is a
DSP mode that kind of makes everything
sound farther away, so it's less
distracting and and on your ears,
whereas cinema mode is meant to be like
more immersive, big sound for your
cinema. I don't know. Personally, I'm
not big into DSP effects, but your
mileage may vary. Oh, you can tell like
which locations you want to hear ambient
sound or you do want to hear speech or
you want complete isolation or whatever.
Speak to chat. Oh, all right. Cool. All
right. So, when I'm like talking, it's
all like, okay, it takes like a second
to kick in and then let's see uh if you
guys say something to me. Hi, Lionus.
Yeah. Okay, I can hear you. How are you?
All right. Yeah. No, I'm I'm done with
conversation now. Oh, okay. About 15
seconds. Okay. So, that that that gives
a minute. So, realistically, I mean, if
someone's lecturing at you for longer
than 15 seconds without you interacting
with them, realistically, you probably
want it to kick in anyway. So, Oh, damn.
Touch sensor. Nice. Just like that. So
intuitive. Head gesture.
Nod to accept. Shake to reject. Yeah.
Okay, cool. Off from the headphones are
removed. Okay. The whole detection of
whether you're wearing them or not thing
did cause some challenges in our
testing. See, you can't run the A and C
on these unless they detect that they
are on a human head. But active noise
cancellation affects the frequency
response and therefore the sound quality
of the headphones. So, we wanted to be
able to measure with A&C. So, we had to
actually trick it by packing one of the
ear cups with like a bunch of copper
tape and then just measuring the other
side. Then, we measured both sides to
make sure that they were well matched so
that we could actually trust that
frequency response curve. And the
results are as good as we can get them
for you. Now, now, do I finally get to
listen to them? You know, when you said
the bass was overemphasized, I kind of
expected a lot worse than this. No, it's
uh pleasing to the point where bass
heads might even find themselves playing
around with different EQ modes. Ooh,
manual. A buddy. It's really nice to
have this functionality built in. You
can't take it for granted. So, if you
want to tune them to be a little bit
more dumpy than you can, man. You know
what I like most about good noise
cancellation is that I don't have to
crank my music. I don't have to put my
hearing at risk in order to clearly hear
every layer of the song. I have this at
what would basically be like kind of
background music level. And now I am
oblivious. These guys could be having a
loud conversation about how much they
all hate their mother-in-laws or
whatever kind of that I don't want
to know about, right? I don't care. I'm
doing my thing. I would have no idea.
That's pretty cool. Somebody Somebody
pretend to be a crying baby. I'm going
to put up my hand when I think you're
crying.
Reese,
you have to do it. This is for the
production.
Well, I think I got one. What else is
there in our draft labs testing? By the
way, we are so open to your guys'
feedback. We'll have a link down to the
blog post that'll probably accompany
this version of our of our testing,
which I think is what, 0.6, something
like that. Labs described the sound
profile as not V-shaped, but somewhere
between V-shaped and a little bit bass
heavy, but even then, not bass heavy
either. Not bloated. I got to tell you,
my impression of the sound profile of
these is that it's kind of like it's the
equivalent of watching a movie in
filmmaker mode, but just a little bit
more fun. No one actually really wants
to listen to music day in day out on
studio monitors. Train training. Oh,
okay. Sure. Apparently, there's a train.
The microphone performance was a bright
spot. There is a little bit of extra
emphasis in the treble, but that's to be
expected since it really wants to pick
up human voices for speech and not
really pick up the traffic around you.
And we found that the clarity and lack
of artifacts was actually quite a strong
point for these. I realize now that I
haven't really looked at any of Sony's
talking points. This was technically a
sponsored video, but we did include a
lot of like labs testing and stuff. Up
to 3 hours of playback on 3 minutes of
charging with optional USB PD compatible
AC charger. Nice. Oh, dude. I didn't
even think of that. The bass
compensation thing could be great if you
wear glasses. That totally makes sense.
I was like, "Oh, yeah." So, you know, if
you suck at putting on headphones or
whatever, it'll compensate for that. But
no, totally. If you have, you know, a
hairstyle or if you have glasses or
whatever that interferes with getting a
good seal, okay, that's super cool.
Subscribe to Short Circuit. We'll have
these linked down below.